Welcome to Startup School 2026. Now,
let's get started.
Please join me in welcoming to the stage
the founder and CEO of Nvidia, Jensen
Huang.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hey Jensen.
>> [music]
>> Please.
Everybody.
>> Oh my god.
This is a surreal moment for me. Thank
you. Thank you for being here, Jensen.
>> I'm delighted to do it. It's great to be
here.
>> [cheering]
>> Apparently,
if you're here,
you are going to make it.
So, I'm happy I'm here.
>> [laughter]
>> Oh, Jensen. Uh
Well, for the students who only know
Nvidia at this as a company at the
center of AI,
uh what part of the early Nvidia story
do they most need to understand?
>> The thing that most people don't
don't believe is that
that um
uh the choice of our technology that we
started the company with was absolutely
wrong.
And so, we had started with the idea
that we would reinvent 3D graphics.
Well, the the company's
philosophy and perspective
uh was that
the general purpose computers, the CPUs,
were really useful, but if we could
augment it with uh accelerators, we
could solve problems that otherwise
too hard to solve.
And one of the first problems we chose
was 3D graphics.
And we And during that time 1993 the PC
was just rumored to be coming.
And
and our big idea was that we would turn
every single personal computer into a
game console because we grew up in the
era of game consoles.
And so we thought you know what if we
could could
design a system that would fit into the
personal computer
and it would turn it into a game
console. And so we thought we would
reinvent the algorithm that would
require these large supercomputers and
we would fit it into the PC.
And we came up with some new algorithms.
And we were excited about it. We
believed in it. It was we reasoned about
it
um in a thoughtful way.
And
and we went to start the company to go
build it. Well, it turns out the
algorithm was exactly wrong.
And the technology that founded the
company turns out to be exactly wrong.
And so in 1995
uh we realized that and
it was almost too late because by then
there were some 35 40 other companies
that were building 3D graphics for PCs.
And and so we realized that it didn't
work and I went back to the company and
we were at the company I said what are
we going to do? It doesn't work and we
were all talking about it and I said
look uh we we uh
we won't have a company if we don't
confront the fact that this doesn't work
and start working towards the right
algorithm.
And and then somebody told me it turns
out none of us knew how to do it the
right way.
And not only did we choose the wrong
technology we didn't know how to do it
the right way. And so
so that that was a big day for me. I had
a couple of couple of $60 you know a
couple of $100 in my pocket and so I
went down to Fry's and I bought three
textbooks.
And and the textbooks was about OpenGL
and how to design uh pipelines. I
brought it back to the company and gave
it to the engineers,
and here we are. Uh we reinvented
computer graphics, we're the world
leader in modern computer graphics, we
invented most of the major breakthroughs
in the last 25 years.
Everybody would have thought that Nvidia
is
you know started out as world leaders in
3D graphics, and we learned it from a
textbook.
And so we actually started the company,
raised money,
and bought textbooks.
When you think about it. And so the the
the big lesson is that for me is
technology is changing all the time,
and
so long as you're able to confront the
reality, so long as you are able to
learn, the technology itself actually
doesn't matter.
And so uh since then Nvidia has been,
you know,
inventing all kinds of technology since,
all kinds of technology we've never
never really done before, and we
approach everything with the same
attitude, you know, this is uh if it's
important to do, we're going to go learn
it, and how hard can it be?
And uh it always turns out to be much
much harder than
than uh we expect. Um but you go into it
with the attitude, how hard can it be?
>> I mean, backstage we were uh talking
about how I mean, we were talking with
some of the top YC companies, and you
were saying that each one has an
expertise in like a domain that you have
an you and Nvidia have an expertise in,
and they're all just I I forget what you
said, it was like an algorithmic domain
of a sort. And so it sounds like 3D
graphics was merely the first of an
algorithmic domain.
>> That's right.
>> came from a textbook, but then,
you know, anyone could have read that
textbook. You created
>> Particle physics, fluid dynamics, yeah.
>> But you created the the thing that
people want, like the the end product
that people want to pay a lot of money
for.
>> The big idea of the company that was
spot-on is that it is possible to
augment the CPU to solve problems that
otherwise are too difficult to solve.
And and molecular dynamics is one of
them, image processing is one of them,
inverse physics is another one. And so
all kinds of different algorithms, of
course deep learning is one of the major
ones. And and um
in order to create the company that we
have today, we realized early on
uh that it's not about building a great
chip, it's about accelerating an
algorithm domain.
And so one of the things I've always
believed believed in is what makes great
companies is a unique perspective about
the world that you deeply believe in.
It's not so much the technology, it's
not so much uh the market even. Uh those
things all matter and if you have the
right technology for the right market at
the right time, uh your life is going to
be a lot easier.
A high-level vision about the future of
some important thing, a perspective
about it that's somehow unique,
that you deeply believe in and ideally
pursuing that that vision is hard to do,
those are kind of good good
combinations. In our case, we realized
that accelerated computing was going to
be important. And accelerated computing
turns out uh to be very important and
our realization is everything to do with
algorithm, not the chip. Uh turns out to
be exactly right.
>> So you've said a lot about I guess the
hardships of a founder. Um
are there a few stories that really jump
out at you? I mean there the people in
this room would love to start a company,
but you know, are they really prepared
for eating glass and you know, possibly
having to shut down the company, like
things going wrong? Like what are some
of the pivotal moments that really jump
out at you?
I think you were just in Japan, right?
And uh
>> Yeah.
>> you were sort of um
honoring uh Sega, was it? So I feel like
that was a really powerful story.
>> The project that led us to realize the
algorithm we chose was wrong was a
partnership with Sega. Sega
uh had contracted us
to build the
uh game console after Saturn
that turned out to have been Dreamcast.
I don't know if Does anybody know what
Dreamcast is?
Okay.
So, we did not build Dreamcast. We were
originally supposed to build Dreamcast.
But because our algorithm and our
technology was fundamentally flawed, I
went to Japan and I told Irimajiri-san,
the CEO at the time, that that the
contract that they gave us was a like
$12 million
contract, um
we will not be able to to fulfill
because the technology doesn't work.
And I told him the reasons why.
And then I advised that
that uh they choose somebody else to do
it.
Uh but then I asked them
uh I told him that I unfortunately still
need the money. And he he asked me,
"Hey,
you know, the conver- You could just
imagine the conversation. So, what
you're telling me is
what I contracted you to to do, uh you
can't do, uh but you would like all the
money
on the contract." And I said, "You got
it. That's exactly right."
>> [laughter]
>> But obviously I was polite. I was I was
humble.
And he realized that that um
I was honest and and and and uh
everything made sense.
I And if he didn't give us the money,
we'd be out of business.
And I think that uh this happens in this
room. You don't invest in companies, you
invest in people. And what Irimajiri uh
recognized was here's, you know,
somebody and a company that uh he
trusted in the first place the contract
and that he believed in
and um that he would love to see, you
know, uh make it make it to the next
day. And so, that $5 million kept us
alive and, you know, gave me enough time
to discover what to do.
>> And then I guess if they held they sold
it for 15 million I heard.
>> Yeah, they sold it the moment we went
public. Uh when Nvidia went public our
valuation was 300 million dollars.
300 million dollars in 1999. That was
real money.
>> I think it's uh north of a trillion
dollars now or so.
>> It's more than a trillion, yeah.
>> Yeah, that's wild.
So,
you're sort of the core, you know, I we
like to say that you're uh you're the
man who controls the spice.
Um
you know, before that, you know, I don't
think anyone could have really predicted
per se um how important uh GPUs and you
know, the technology you built would be
for this AI revolution.
Um
you know, what did you see to I mean,
was it the accelerator and being in the
right place right time or surely there
were a lot of things that led up to that
that allowed you to sort of capture this
position?
>> Yeah.
Uh
I saw AlexNet just like everybody else
saw AlexNet. And and um
I but remember,
our lens of the world, my view of the
world was always looking for algorithms.
And that algorithm
the algorithm could be NAMDI, the
algorithm could be VASP, the algorithm
could be OpenGL.
You know, it could be SQL, some domain
specific language, some algorithm.
And and so my lens of the world was
always looking for some uh problem that
we might be able to help solve. So, when
AlexNet came along, the algorithm was
deep learning. And so, the question is
what is this algorithm and why does it
matter? Why was it so um effective and
what else can it do?
And and if you were to scale algorithms
and scale it beyond that, uh what could
it solve that otherwise you can't solve
today? And and the the breakthrough for
us was realizing that AlexNet was not
AlexNet. That AlexNet was an approach
with deep deep learning that allows you
to learn any function. And so, 15 years
ago, I was telling everybody that, "Hey,
guess what? We just learned the
universal function approximator."
We just discovered the universal
function approximator. We can give it We
could, you know, give it the the answer
for almost any function and it could
learn what the function is.
And for a lot of functions, you don't
have to be precise. And in fact, it's
impossible to be precise. And so, most
of the interesting problems are
imprecise in this way.
And so,
um the day that we realized we have a
universal function approximator, the
question then is what is that what is
that what is that uh do to the computing
stack? What does that happen to
software? What are the industries that
this could impact? So on and so forth.
Um almost right away,
we started working on computer vision.
Almost right away, we started working on
robotics, um self-driving cars because
I
that fundamental capability, you could
imagine solving some imp- important
problems in the area of computer vision
and robotics. And so, so I think I think
the the big breakthrough was simply that
this is much more foundational than
AlexNet. This is a way of doing
software.
And the implications to the processor,
the middleware, the algorithms, the
applications, you know, what I now
describe as the five-layer cake, um that
entire industrial stack, I imagine
reinventing all all together about 15
years ago. And this is simply about
asking questions, reasoning about things
to first principles, uh asking, you
know, questions like, "If this, then
what?" Uh if if this can get better,
then so what? You know, asking all of
the basic questions about about
something that you observe uh that's
really impactful.
>> I mean, one of the things that really
jumps out at me is to what degree you go
all the way into the weeds. You read
papers, you you know, talk directly to
the principal scientists who are sort of
coming up with these things. Do you have
any advice for people in the audience? I
mean, that's like true founder mode. And
then at the same time, you probably you
have an organization and you have
executives and you have people who say
like, here's the graph, we want to stay
on this graph. You know, sometimes it
ruffles feathers. Like, do you have any
advice for people about an organization
and how you
navigate that really? Like, how do you
build an org that allows you to think in
first principles? Cuz if the Fortune 500
did that, like, the Fortune 500 will
probably look a lot more like Nvidia
than not. And it doesn't. Like, you you
have built a very unique company.
>> My state of mind when I'm my state of
mind is always
starts with curiosity.
I have a whole bunch of questions
myself.
And and
of course
like anybody else, I'll seek the
shortest path to the answer.
But often times
the answers from the people that are
near me might not be satisfying and and
I might have other questions and and
maybe they're they're busy doing
something and they're pursuing
something.
And so my first my first
inclination is to go discover the
answers to my own curiosity.
My second is if I find that the
information is in that the domain of
information or you know, particular
field
could be really important to somebody
and could be important to our company,
then my next inclination is how can I
learn as much as possible so that I
could be of service to the company and
share with the everybody else.
You know, this is no different than than
you when you're you're sharing
knowledge. I mean, I watch your podcasts
and I watch your your videos and I
really enjoy them. You're sharing ideas
with everybody else. You know, in a lot
of ways I think a
a CEO is in service of the company, in
service of all the people that are
working there. And you want to empower
them with some insight.
And so that's really where it's coming
from. It's not so much a management
technique, but a personality technique.
You know, I I want to empower you and
this is something really important that
I just observed. Let me tell you why
it's so important.
Now part of part of having to to be near
the ground and be in the weeds if you
will,
is because often times the technology is
complicated or it's changing really
fast.
And especially when it's changing fast
like like our world, um unless you have
a tactile
sensation of what is actually happening,
it could either to you feel like it's
just moving way too fast to understand.
But if you understand the first
principles of it over time, then
everything kind of makes sense.
You know, it's kind of like surfing I
would imagine. I don't know how to surf,
but I can imagine it's kind of like
surfing. You get out on the wave. To me
it looks like chaos, but to a surfer,
you know, somehow they get right? They
can read the waves and and uh they know
how to stay on top of it. And so I think
being CEO is very similar to that. You
know, you have to learn how to surf and
order to learn how to surf you have to
understand the waves. You have to be
able to read the wind and you have to
have good timing and you can't have any
of that unless you try unless you
actually do it. And so so partly is is
to inform myself, partly is to uh try to
figure out, you know, what is try to
break down the problem so that the
company can learn it in a way that they
can do something about. Uh part of it is
about inspiring other people.
And um
you know, it's it's all those those uh
basic traits of all the people in this
room. You don't have to change your
personality or your behavior
uh when you become CEO. It is possible
for you to continue to be yourself.
And one of the things that I that I I
learned a long time ago
um
and and I I have no idea where I saw
this.
Uh
but
but um
you know, the CEO or the founders
you are the you you're building a car
that you are going to race.
You're going to build an F1 racer, but
you're going to build it in a way that
you can drive.
You should adapt the car to you.
You know, somebody I think had asked me
uh you know, Jenson, if you
if you don't use
conventional management techniques and
organizational techniques
you know, what's going to happen when
you leave the company?
Well, you know, when I die on the job
um
someday
uh
you know, I told them they'll just have
to reshape the company for the next CEO.
And the reason that's wisdom is because
we're the F1 drivers.
You know, we're the racers.
And the world is really competitive and
we've got to stay we've got to you know,
we've got to win.
And we've got to achieve our mission.
And so whatever it takes to fit the car
to you
whatever it takes to fit the
organization to you, that's what you got
to do. And the next CEO, whatever the
personality is, they can figure it out.
>> Amazing. I mean, that it does seem like
um
any change you make to the car will just
slow you down and lose you races that
you know, isn't fit to you.
>> Yeah, or we're constantly tweaking the
car to our needs. And I'm that's really
what I'm doing all the time. I'm
constantly tweaking the company,
constantly reshaping business processes
and the way things work so that I can
you know, be more effective for the
company.
>> True founder mode.
>> Yeah, founder mode. Founder mode could
scale for 34 years.
>> That's right.
>> From zero to 5 trillion.
No evidence. No
>> [applause]
>> I'd love to switch gears to like what
you know, what are the what are the
frontier algorithms that you're most
interested in now? I mean Um, I love
that you're all the way down into the
material science, all the way up into
the app level.
Uh, you know, you're the first to speak
on stage about Open Claw and now Hermes
agent. Um,
I wonder if you can sort of like walk us
through a day in the life of like how
you think about the different stages. I
mean, going from materials to chips to
data centers to even like the app level,
like how people are going to work. Like
there's sort of this idea of a full
stack AI factory.
>> Well,
this is one of the things that that is
probably going to be the most useful
skill in the future. And in fact, just
in listening to you talk about about
technology and and you your use of it,
you know, one of the most important
things is systems understanding.
Systems awareness, system design, system
organization.
Um,
but systems thinking.
And the reason for that is because
most of the low-level things that that
has to be done are going to be done
agentically anyways. They're going to be
automated anyhow. And so, whether it's,
you know, in my generation it's about
compiling chips and synthesizing
transistors and gates and functional
blocks and
and all of that is now synthesized. And
so, most of our designers are systems
designers.
In the case of software,
uh, most software is going to be done
agentically anyhow. So, you have to be
much more
able to think abstractly about systems.
What are the what are the the problems
you're trying to solve? What are the
constraints? Where, you know, where's
where's the input? Where's the output?
You know, where information coming from?
Um, what is the rate of of uh,
information flowing in and out of the
system? Uh, what are the constraints?
Um, you know, and so
is it processor? Is it memory? Is it
networking? Uh,
you know, and so under
these
uh systems problems at a sufficiently
technical level is going to be very
helpful to all of the people in this
room. And I don't think that that that
way of that fundamental knowledge is
ever going to be useless. I think it's
going to be more and more useful. And so
I
I try to understand systems um
the best I can. One of the things
One of the things that speaking of
agent,
the fact of the matter is we we kind of
have coarse level
uh recursive self-improvement already.
And the fact that every time you use it,
it improves the markdown files. Uh every
time you use it, it updates its
uh long-term memory. And the long-term
memory is being processed either either
compacted or turned into knowledge
graphs or, you know, so on and so forth.
Uh it's being improved all the time.
Uh
you know, asynchronously. And so
the agent's getting smarter smarter
every time. Still, the problem is and
this is one of the one of the problems
that I think it'd be helpful for
everybody to solve is how can we have
very very specific fine-grained control?
You know, if not for rags, if not for
conditional inputs, if not for our all
of our prompts
um directly into output was was too
coarse.
And so the fact that we can condition,
the fact that we can control the agents
um all the way down to eventually uh
when it comes up with a plan, I change
one word in a plan file, and that one
word makes
a delta difference.
Not complete difference, but specific
difference. Um maybe it's one pixel,
maybe it's one triangle, maybe it's one
component in a CAD file, maybe one
layer, one via, one connection.
And then it regenerates everything else.
I think that that level of control and
that level of collaboration with agents
will be game changing. We don't need the
the agents to be 100% accurate, 100%
high quality in order for us to use it.
It could, you know, literally be 80% and
then we help it the rest of the way, or
it could be 99% we help it the rest of
the way. And so I I think
controllability is probably the single
biggest breakthrough
that we need for agents at every single
level.
>> Do you think people will like I mean,
with Hermes or Open Claw, it feels like
that might actually be somewhat
existential. Like people should control
their own personal AGI. Like they
shouldn't outsource that app and, you
know, have it be just in the cloud and
someone else's agent that like kind of
tells you what to do. Like you kind of
want it to be your own.
>> Yeah. Is that part of the thrust behind
Nvidia being so involved in
>> I think well, first of all, I I need to
understand agents because agents is the
new software. And how is this new
software processed matters a lot
>> to computer architecture.
>> And the the more intimate we are about
um the nature of agents and how it's
different than than um
uh chatbots, which is how different than
than um maybe inference in the very
beginning. However, we think about these
processing layers, the more intimate we
are about the nature of the processing,
the better we can design systems.
We we kind of have to live in the future
5 to 10 years because it takes three or
so years just to build a system, takes a
couple years to ramp it up, and you're
dealing and you would like them to be
able to use the computer for 10 years
after. And so you kind of have to live
in the future for a while. And so
agentic systems for us at the first
principles is just what is the workload,
what's the algorithm, how is it going to
evolve, where are the bottlenecks, you
know, where are the Amdahl's law's
problems, and um
how How it scale, uh what happens to
concurrency? How do you deal with
sandboxes?
How do you deal with MCP? How do you
deal with
you know, working memory, long-term
memory? How do you have all these
autonomous systems, asynchronous systems
working all the time?
And so, what kind of design architecture
makes perfect sense for that? And so, we
have to go and go discover that.
And then, of course, the second thing is
I want to use agents ourselves to make
NVIDIA go faster. And so, we have, you
know, voices in the back
and we've got cloud code autonomously
running in sandboxes all over NVIDIA,
and that's really fantastic.
And some people use code codex, some
people use cloud code, some people use
cursor, some people use cognition. And
and we we let kind of a a thousand
flowers bloom, let people select the
tools they want to use, and then we
learn from from all of that. And so, the
second part is just helping the company
move faster.
Use the tools, and the more they use it,
the more you're going to learn about
how to make it work better in the
future. And then the last part is is
discovering the future of of um
solutions technology for the future. And
maybe you know, when we when we saw
when we saw the early versions of of
chain of thought come out of Stanford,
it was probably a decade ago at this
point, maybe eight years ago.
You know, the question is
is
how how effective is that going to be in
reasoning, and how scalable is going to
be?
And what is the implication, for
example, in computer vision,
if we can reason
from prior knowledge.
And and then the big breakthrough, of
course, is just in in thinking through
that small little domain, you come to
realize that maybe we don't need as much
data for cars to train a self-driving
car.
Which led us to creating Alpaca My which
is the world's first thinking
self-driving car.
And with just a million miles or so, a
couple million miles, it's an incredibly
great self-driving car. And the reason
for that is it's kind of like us, right?
We don't need that many miles before
uh we could drive fairly well most of
our lives. And the reason for that is
because we have prior knowledge from our
language model, and we can decompose um
a situation we've never seen before, uh
and um I and build it up uh out of
things that we understood and know very
well. And so So, that that's an example
of seeing something and then realizing
the impacts on sometime later. Uh when
the agentic systems came along, uh it's
very very clear
that obviously a large language models
uh needs memory, it needs prior
knowledge, it needs tools, it needs ways
to network with other agents. And so,
that kind of, you know, that once you
see some early indicators, uh and you're
able to reason about the future, uh
helps you get a leap, you know, into
into the future.
>> I I I feel like there's this pattern
that I'm starting to see around Nvidia.
It's like you see a problem, there's a
new algorithm, there's some new thing
happening, and then actually you're
right there with open source. I mean, I
remember when OpenCL came out and people
said it was unsafe, but you guys came
out with uh sandboxing sort of uh
toolkit that like surrounds any harness
and makes it safe. And so,
>> When I saw OpenCL, my first thought was
Well, first of all, I I I learned about
it. And then and then um
you know, without without much
imagination, you just realized we just
designed the modern computer. This is
the operating system that's going to
hold a large language model.
And and um
uh in a lot of ways, OpenCL to me was
very Linux moment to me.
>> Yeah.
>> And now everybody can build their own
AI. And I was so excited about that. And
we contacted Peter, and um we said,
"Hey, you know, all of Nvidia's
engineers are your engineers.
That's what I told Peter.
You got this battleship outside your
house. You you
you know, break down the problem as you
desire and we'll contribute as as you
wish.
Same thing with the the the Hermes team.
You know, and I'm so excited about the
work that they're doing.
I do think that the world needs
the ability for everybody to build their
own AI.
And you could you could of course
and I encourage everybody to to use
cloud services as much as possible.
Everybody should use chat GPT and Claude
and right, everybody should use that.
And but if you if you need to build your
own AI because you're a company and and
you need to build your own domain
specific AIs. Now you have Hermes and
you have open Claude, you've got all
kinds of you got LangChain, deep agent,
you got all these different ways, right?
To build your own AI. And it's it's
quite frankly relatively easy because
the software is smart.
You know, and so AI smart and therefore
AI must be so smart you could adapt it
easily. And so I I think that that we
want we want to encourage everybody and
every company to build their own AIs.
And and and who knows what innovation
will come from the fact that it's open
source.
>> I feel like all the alpha is in building
your own AI. I mean, if someone else is
using whatever is off the shelf, but
you're you have a thing that can
recursively self-improve and it is, you
know, I mean, the mech people are very
flippant about market markdown files.
They say like, oh haha, it's just text,
but like text is intelligence.
And we're in a different
>> Words are thoughts.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, words are thoughts.
>> Yeah, and it turns out you can
>> Try to try to think without words.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> [laughter]
>> So switching gears again, I mean, a lot
of people are
anytime you move the cheese, people get
a little worried.
Intelligence is going to be on tap,
which is really awesome. I think it
bodes well for everyone in this room.
Um,
what do you think changes about the
economy? What do you think, you know,
happens in sort of a broader sense?
>> Uh, obviously, what I'm going to say is
uneven. Uh, there are some uh, you know,
we're going to automate tasks.
We're going to automate cognitive tasks.
If that task is uh, somebody makes a
phone call and and sends a bunch of
words,
you know, across the phone to you and
your job is to provide a response. And
and um, if all the information is at
your fingertip because you you have all
the database here and you should be able
to to answer that question completely.
Uh, in that case, that task will be
automated away. Okay? Ignoring that for
a second. Not that Not that you Not that
we we ignore this, but my my point is
I'm going to answer the question about
about really the great opportunity. And
so, um, many tasks will be automated
away. Um, many jobs Every single job
will be will change and there'll be a
whole bunch of new jobs and that that
that I think we know. Um, the bottom
line is this.
The evidence would show that and it
makes perfect sense that AI and
automation is creating jobs everywhere.
The narrative about AI destroying jobs
is exactly backwards. AI eliminate
tasks.
AI automates tasks away.
But it doesn't necessary
doesn't necessarily eliminate jobs. And
the reason for that is because the the
job of a person has a purpose and that
purpose has many tasks. Some of those
tasks could be automated away. Many of
those tasks cannot be.
And so, the evidence suggests that here
we are, we've automated coding, which is
a task,
but the job of a software engineer
appears to be growing, right? The number
of software engineer jobs year over year
has increased 10%.
The task of reading radiology scans
has been automated, but the number of
radiology jobs has increased some 20% in
the last several years,
even though AI's taken over the whole
field. And the reason for that
is because the backlog of patients
is incredibly high. Now doctors and
hospitals could admit a lot more
patients. In order to admit a lot more
patients, you need more nurses, more
radiologists.
And so, the same thing with software. We
hit the backlog of ideas, the backlog of
ambition and aspiration
is so high that if we can automate away
the task of programming, we could hire
more software engineers to do more
things. We could be more ambitious.
Same thing all you know, just across the
board.
Uh they said Harvey is going to
eliminate all of the paralegal jobs, and
the number of lawyers will be
reduced. Turns out paralegals are
growing like crazy. And the reason for
that is because the backlog of lawsuits
is really high, and now these law firms
could get a lot more cases through.
And in order to do so, you got to hire
more people. And so, this is a classic
classic example of productivity
increasing growth. Increasing growth
drives more employment. This is the
reason why there's more employment today
than there was when I first came out of
school.
>> So, we've been talking a lot about
software and agents. Um
another really exciting thing that
Nvidia is all the way out on the edge on
is actually physical robots. Um
you know, how far out? I think in the
past you might have even said um
this as soon as this year. What's the
latest thinking on, you know, when can
we expect practical robotics?
>> Yeah, the moment that I saw as
generating video,
that was
that was a great moment for me. The
moment that I and I start I saw as
generating video, I mean, we did the
original work on
um auto
uh progressive GANs, okay? And we did
the original work on uh conditional
GANs. Um long before the first videos
were generated outside that people saw,
um a couple of years earlier inside our
labs, we were driving a a uh simulator
completely generated by video. And
computer completely generated by neural
networks. And so, the moment I saw
us generating articulation,
if I can generate video of a finger
moving, if I could generate video of a
hand picking up a glass, why can't I
cause a robot to do the same?
And so, the moment I saw that generative
AI happening, I realized that robotics
articulation was around the corner.
And so, now the question is, you know,
how's the robot going to understand
uh
to generate motions that obey the laws
of physics? How's it How does it
understand causality? Um how does it
understand, you know, friction, tension?
How does it understand the laws of
physics? And so, it started us down the
journey of creating what we call
physical AI now. And everybody calls it
physical AI. And physical AI, uh we
started working on world foundation
model,
um an AI that understands the laws of
physics and the how the world works. And
um uh we started down the the journey of
of uh working on robotics. I would say
the chat GPT moment of robots happened a
couple of years ago already.
>> Wow.
>> And and the reason for that is remember
when chat GPT first came out,
it didn't do anything productive.
It didn't do anything useful, but it
opened our imagination about what's
possible. And I would say a couple of
years ago, you know, robots walking
around that we could do reinforcement
learning, fine-tune it for and ground it
in physics, uh really happened a couple
of years ago.
So, now what what do we need to do? We
need to do all the same things that
we're doing now for agentic systems.
We have to create environments for them
to learn in, to eval in, eval against.
And so, we have to do real to sim to
create environments.
Uh we have to do uh
uh we have to generate simulators that
are based on simulation, grounded
physics simulation, as well as
generative uh physics simulations. And
so, uh Isaac Sim, uh Cosmos, and all the
work that we do in that area is related
to simulation. And then the last part is
sim to real. And so, uh that part is has
something to do with reinforcement
learning, um uh grounding it on physics,
uh grounding it on grounding it on all
on um all the electromechanical
uh systems that that robots require. And
so, but these three basic system, I I
think builds up uh the eval, if you
will, the the the the post-training of
um of robotics. And I I think we're
we're going to see it right around the
corner.
>> Amazing. Where does physical AI show up
first in a way that's really
economically real? Are you seeing that
already?
>> We conjectured that uh
that robotics was going to come along
and decided that the first application
of robotics that has both a large enough
market,
um relatively standardized
technology so that we could scale and
get the flywheel going,
um and has real economic value was uh
self-driving cars. And so, uh inside
Waymo, uh our chips from Nvidia. Uh at
at Tesla, we were in the car. Uh now
we're in the data center. Um uh
Mercedes, we're in the data center,
we're in the car with a software stack.
Uh we uh uh worked on Alpaca Myo, and we
open-sourced it. And the reason why we
open-sourced the self-driving car stack
is because you need it for agriculture,
you need it for mail delivery, you need
it for warehouse AMRs. There's so many
different ways that you could apply um,
uh, autonomous
navigation
uh, and none of those markets are big
enough to be a self-driving car market
and we thought it was
sufficiently diverse that we would
create the whole stack for it. And so
we're working with autonomous vehicles
in all kinds of different places.
Our robotics business, autonomous
vehicle business, basically physical AI
business is probably almost like $10
billion. So it's really, really big
already.
Um, likely this will be one of the
largest industries in the world and um,
uh, it'll take longer than a couple two,
three years. It'll take less than 10.
And so this will this will be our next
$100 billion business.
>> Amazing.
Um, I want to take a moment. Uh, I think
this is the exact right crowd to uh,
you know, maybe as a arena we can
welcome Jensen to X.
Welcome to X. I mean, you made your
first post uh, and thank you for your
leadership.
>> [applause]
>> You know, that's that just that shows
you how introverted I am.
It took me until 2026 to have the first
post on X.
You know, it's I'm probably the last
human on Earth that that did it.
Uh, but but uh, what I posted was too
important to me and too important to the
to the industry and too important to the
world. And so so uh, I I over overcame
my um, my shyness and and put my first
thing out on X.
>> No, thank you for your leadership. I
mean, open source, open weights, open
source models are incredibly important
for
I mean, what all of us in this room want
to do. Like we want to create products.
>> If not for open source, the mobile cloud
industry would have never happened.
If not for open, if not for Linux, if
not for Kubernetes, if not for all of
these, you know, platform, if not for
uh, TensorFlow or more important, uh,
PyTorch,
right? The and the early versions of a
cafe, right? Torch. I mean, all of the
Theano. Remember the early versions of
all Those were all open source. If not
for all of that, how would we have
modern AI?
>> Well, thank you for your leadership and
your voice is incredibly important here.
Thank you.
>> [applause]
[applause]
>> Before we go, I feel like we I just
really resonate with your story. I think
that everyone here, but I mean, would
love the wisdom of,
you know, your journey coming here. I
mean, what should a young person learn
now, given all the things that you're
seeing, all the algorithms that are
going to take hold in society? Um
what should a young person learn now
that will still matter, based on what
you're seeing?
>> Well, some of the things that I saw
today
and some of the starters I met today was
really really quite quite encouraging
and
and and the thing that that um
the big takeaway is, of course,
the simple stuff is going to get
automated away.
And when I say simple stuff, I mean,
software, you know, coding.
Uh
the idea that you would you would do a
you would solve a problem by sitting in
front of a computer and you're you're
actually writing, you know, writing
code, that concept is obviously going to
get automated away.
Um you know,
in my generation, when I was when I was
growing up, we had to do long division.
I mean, for God's sakes, who has to
learn long division, you know? And so,
that got coded away, that got automated
away. And so, I think the simple stuff
is going to get automated away, but the
hard problems, the hard sciences, um
physics, chemistry, biology, uh you
know, computer science, uh computer
engineering, systems thinking,
uh you know, all and and particularly
the domains that are intersecting,
uh those hard problems will never go
away. And so, AI is just an incredible
tool that helps us become even more
ambitious.
Even more um impatient about solving
these extraordinarily large and
incredibly hard problems
uh than before. And so, you know, if you
if you look at my generation,
when I first graduated,
a chip designer would design a chip with
maybe a thousand transistors, and that
would be a very large chip.
You know, now
designing a trillion transistor chips is
not even, you know, if somebody would
have told me, "Jensen, our next chip is
a trillion transistor." I said, "Okay."
You know, it's not a thing.
And the reason for that is because we
are so ambitious now,
the
the scale of the problem, the scale of
the task is no longer a matter.
And so, you don't have to worry about
about, you know,
how much coding, how many engineers. You
don't have to You don't have to think
about those things anymore. You just
have to think about what is the what is
the problem you have to solve. And so, I
think that the deep deep tech stuff, the
deep science stuff, uh understanding
understanding the intersection between
technology and social issues, um
understanding market market gaps and and
holes, uh opportunities, I think all of
that still exists.
Um and and the better you are at systems
thinking so that you could orchestrate
millions of agents solving problems
autonomously, the better off you are.
And so, that's why system thinking is
going to be so important. But uh
otherwise, I think the world's going to
continue to have a lot of great
challenges for us to solve. Go to school
the same old way.
You know, stay in school.
>> Stay in school.
>> [applause]
>> I guess um I usually like to end with um
you're looking out on the crowd. There
are a lot of people who
uh I mean,
I started this uh the opener with like I
honestly look in the crowd and I see
people who are not different than us per
se, You know, we actually just
are technical and like love systems.
How you know
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> What advice would you give to this room
of, you know,
And you you see yourself in this in this
room and like I'm curious what you would
say. If you could send a
telegram, a message to the 18 to
22-year-old version of yourself, what
would that be?
>> I could tell you exactly how I felt when
I first when Nvidia founded and and the
three of us started. Um
The the thing I felt at the time is
there was so much for me to know and so
much for me to learn.
And I didn't know it. And I was telling
you earlier there at the time there was
there were no YouTube, there's you know,
no YC, nobody's teaching you how to
start a company. And so I went to the
bookstore and I bought a book and the
book said, "How to start a company?"
Uh unfortunately, the book was like 500
pages long.
And and so I you know, I figured by the
time I read it, you know, I'd be out of
business. And Lor- Lori and I be out of
money. And so there's no sense reading
it. Um but the thing that the thing I
remember very very vividly is that how
scared I was uh to go raise money
because I felt that I was about to talk
to a bunch of people and I didn't know
how to answer their questions. And um
and it's true. And I barely know how to
answer their questions even today. Uh
but the thing that I learned is
um none of that stuff matters.
As it turns out.
And and you're always going to have
things that you don't know.
And every single day the world's
changing, technology changing.
Obviously, this is the greatest time in
the last 60 years to start a company.
The whole industry has changed. It's a
complete reset from a technology
perspective. The single most important
technology in human history, the
computer, has been completely reset. And
so, this is absolutely the single
greatest time to start a company. And
I'm I'm I'm jealous of all of you.
I and and
and the opportunities you have ahead. I
mean, it's going to be incredible. So,
it's the perfect time on the one hand.
On the other hand, the technology is
changing so fast.
And so, the question is, what's the
right feeling for you? And eventually,
and I told you the story of us of me
buying the other book, the textbook.
I think
the psychology and the feeling that I
have today
on all of the new experiences and the
new technology and new markets and new
dynamics,
I look at it and I say, this is
important. I've got to go learn it.
And I've got to go do something about
it. And I better get to it as fast as I
can.
And how hard can it be?
I always had this feeling, how hard can
it be?
And
truth be told,
it is way harder than you think.
And but you you don't want your mind to
be to be there. You want your mind to
be, how hard can it be?
And let the suffering come to you
a little bit at a time.
You know, don't
don't imagine how hard it's going to be
and let all of that turn into anxiety
and not doing something about it.
You want to imagine your head, how hard
can it be? You know, I've got a whole
bunch of I've got a bunch of AI agents
helping me anyways.
And so, how hard can it be? And then you
get going on working on it. And so,
that's probably the the attitude of an
entrepreneur. You you know you have to
learn a bunch of stuff along the way.
You believe in your ability to learn.
Which is, you know, learning is the
single greatest superpower. And if you
go into it with the attitude, how hard
can it be? If anybody can do it, I can
do it. And just realize that it will be
hard and you just have to have the
resilience to overcome it every single
day. You don't have to overcome life in
one day. You just have to overcome that
morning. That morning, you know, you
have to overcome today today. And so
it's not a big deal. Just get through
today. Wait till right? Work towards
tomorrow. Keep following your dreams.
And the rest of everything if you stick
if you stick with it long enough,
uh you know, Nvidia happens.
And so, you know, I think that the
wisdom
that I can
if it there's anything is resilience is
probably the single most important
thing.
And if you believe in something, just
get going on it and get your mind
you know, out of out of keeping your
yourself from pursuing it
because of you know, fear or anxiety or
lack of confidence or whatever it is.
And then you're just going to tell
yourself I'm going to learn my way
there.
>> Jensen Huang everybody.
>> All right, guys. Thank you.
>> Thank you so much. Yes, it was
>> Thank you guys.